<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<elements>
	<info>
		<name>Plague Doctor</name>
		<description>Basic background of Champions, chosen warriors of their tribes</description>
		<author url="https://www.dmsguild.com/product/171285/The-Plague-Doctor-a-dark-fantasy-background">Pilleri Federico</author>
		<update version="0.0.1">
			<file name="plaguedoctor-background.xml" url="https://github.com/Pant0stad0/The-Plague-Doctor-A-new-dark-fantasy-background/edit/master/plaguedoctor-background.xml" />
		</update>
	</info>

	<element name="Plague Doctor" type="Background" source="The Plague Doctor: A new dark fantasy background" id="ID_NV_TGHC_BACKGROUND_PLAGUEDOCTOR">
		<description>
			<p> Plague doctors lead their life in strict contact with death itself; they must come to term with the demise of those they couldn't save.</p>
			<ul>
				<li><strong>Skill Proficiencies:</strong> Medicine, plus one from Investigation and Perception</li>
				<li><strong>Tool Proficiencies:</strong> Healer's Kit, Herbalism Kit</li>
				<li><strong>Equipment:</strong> A healer's kit, a herbalist kit, a set of protective clothes (designed to avoid contagion, they are waxed or made of leather and often associated with a pair of gloves and a very peculiar mask), a sample associated with a rare illness you intend to study, and a bag with pouch containing 10 gp.</li>
			</ul>
			<div element="ID_NV_TGHC_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_RESPECTED_HEALER" />
		</description>
		<rules>
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Skill Proficiency (Plague Doctor)" supports="Skill" number="2" />
			<select type="Proficiency" name="Tool Proficiency (Plague Doctor)" supports="Tool" number="2" optional="true"/>
			<grant type="Background Feature" id="ID_NV_TGHC_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_RESPECTED_HEALER" />
			<select name="Personality Trait" type="List">
				<item id="1">My profession taught me to be very detached, from patients and companions alike.</item>
				<item id="2">Life is a fickle light, we must enjoy it till it lasts.</item>
				<item id="3">People think of me as a jinx, and perhaps they are right: with no plague, there would be no doctor.</item>
				<item id="4">I take note of the physical health of everybody; they'll thank me later for this.</item>
				<item id="5">I prefer not to attract too much attention, unless my work is needed.</item>
				<item id="6">I'm always eager to help.</item>
				<item id="7">Nothing is more satisfying than the gratitude of my patients.</item>
				<item id="8">I simply love black humor, even if nobody else knows when I am joking and when I am referring to something that happened for real.</item>
			</select>
			<select name="Ideal" type="List">
				<item id="1">Greed. I don't give a damn about them and their suffering: all that matters is the money they pay me with, and the power I hold over their life. (Evil)</item>
				<item id="2">Selflessness. If a doctor is needed, I offer my help with no regard for my own health: I swore an oath to my patients, not to myself. (Good)</item>
				<item id="3">Delusion. Death is the only true enemy, an enemy that I will defeat once and for all. (Any)</item>
				<item id="4">Cruelty. The progress of medicine requires some sacrifices: what is the excruciating pain and suffering of a few patients of mine in front of a huge breakthrough in curing every plague?(Evil)</item>
				<item id="5">Fraternity. When facing a plague, all mortals are alike; we should remember this fact even when our lives are safe. (Good)</item>
				<item id="6">Resignation. Every man must die; I can only delay the inevitable. (Any)</item>
			</select>
			<select name="Bond" type="List">
				<item id="1">I'm haunted by the memory of a little patient I was unable to save.</item>
				<item id="2">Once somebody asked me to assist an infamous criminal. I fear I have not heard the last of him.</item>
				<item id="3">I have a sort of rivalry with a colleague, dating back to our apprentice days.</item>
				<item id="4">I fell in love with a patient of mine. Even if this is not very professional, I long for the chance to see my beloved again.</item>
				<item id="5">Some years ago I saved a hamlet from a quite vicious infection; the inhabitants consider me a hero.</item>
				<item id="6">I fear I have discovered a new plague, and sadly I have yet to find a way to cure it.</item>
			</select>
			<select name="Flaw" type="List">
				<item id="1">I fear contagion, any contagion, like death itself.</item>
				<item id="2">First I get paid, then I offer my help.</item>
				<item id="3">I cannot suffer uncleanness, when I have to touch something dirty I feel the urge to wash my hands, even in a dungeon.</item>
				<item id="4">Clerics, gods and their miracles have just to shut up: where was healing magic when my patients got ill?</item>
				<item id="5">I can't refuse a call for help, no matter the situation.</item>
				<item id="6">I tend to speak quite too often about the most disgusting details of my profession.</item>
			</select>
		</rules>
	</element>
	<element name="Feature: Respected Healer" type="Background Feature" source="The Plague Doctor: A new dark fantasy background" id="ID_NV_TGHC_BACKGROUND_FEATURE_RESPECTED_HEALER">
		<description>
			<p>You can make a living by offering your services to the afflicted, be it by the soup offered by the farmer whose daughter had chicken pox, or the banquet offered in your honor by the rich merchant whose disease you cured.</p>
			<p>You know every major pox, illness and disease, but bear in mind that some supernatural or long forgotten plagues will require every inch of your time in order to be kept at bay. However, were you to discover a nonmagical cure against the more vicious plagues, your name will became truly immortal.</p>
		</description>
		<sheet alt="Respected Healer">
			<description>You can make a living by offering your services to the afflicted, be it by the soup offered by the farmer whose daughter had chicken pox, or the banquet offered in your honor by the rich. You know every major pox, illness and disease, but bear in mind that some supernatural or long forgotten plagues will require every inch of your time in order to be kept at bay. However, were you to discover a nonmagical cure against the more vicious plagues, your name will became truly immortal.</description>
		</sheet>
		<rules> 
		</rules>
	</element>
</elements>
